# **DULAN LOKUNARANGODAGE**

#### **SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

dulanwirajith1995@gmail.com

(+94) 76-7996783 (+94) 71-2395553 Colombo, Sri Lanka.

in





#### **SUMMARY**

I am a friendly techie who always has adrenaline in his blood. I am also a skilled, result-oriented individual in the area of Software Development with over 4 years of experience and a strong track record of delivering over 12 successful projects. I have years of experience in leading software development teams from very early-stage startups to scale-ups around the globe including France, Singapore, and Sri Lanka. Currently collaborating as a Senior Software Engineer at CabbageApps.

## **EDUCATION**

## Rajarata University of Sri Lanka

BSc. in Information Technology

**IJSE - Institute of Software Engineering** 

Graduate Diploma in Software Engineering

## Feb 09, 2017 - July 31, 2020

Jan 19, 2016 - Jan 25, 2017

## **COMPUTER LANGUAGE PROFICIENCY**

Node.js, React, JavaScript, TypeScript, NestJS, Angular, Express.js, MongoDB, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Docker, AWS, DigitalOcean, Microservices, REST/SOAP API, Web Sockets, Git, CI/CD Pipeline, GitHub Actions, Agile Methodologies, System Design, Data Structures & Algorithms, Research & Development, Domain Driven Design

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### CabbageApps (Pvt) Ltd, Colombo, Sri Lanka [full-time]

May 07, 2021 - Present

#### Senior Software Engineer

June 01, 2022 - Present

Responsibilities & Achievements:

- Functioning as a Full Stack Developer- Web (Node.js, NestJS, React, Angular, AWS)
- Communicating and collaborating with multi-disciplinary teams of developers, designers, and managers on a daily basis with 90% satisfaction
- Conducted workload assessments and devised new operational processes that led to a 40% increase in productivity
- Accelerate SDLC by 30% through the development of sharable components and libraries

- Developed a back-end project boilerplate, achieving an 80% reduction in the preparation time to initialize the project
- Successfully created and authored Data Aggregation server in TRIBZ project (95% accuracy and 95% uptime)
- Collaborated with a team of 10+ remote developers and senior leadership team to assess project outcomes and prioritize future tasks
- Supervised 3 concurrent projects monitoring each of the development milestones and quality control compilations
- Chaired Tech Talk events and enhanced developers' engagement by 50%

#### Software Engineer

May 07, 2021 – May 30, 2022

Responsibilities & Achievements:

- Focused as a Full Stack Developer Web and Mobile (Node.js, NestJS, React, React Native)
- Restructured boilerplate for Front-end projects that resulted in productivity growth of 40%.
- Delivered an in-house MVP-level product (QA Tool project) within 2 months as the team lead and the product owner in a cross-functional team of 9 people
- Enforced Kanban principles to speed up collaborative teamwork which resulted 25% reduced cycle time
- Refined existing data fetching hook with caching which increased user experience by 30%
- Implemented Ant design custom components to generate form schema functions which reduced code duplication by 25% and error margin by 10%
- Seen as the most comfortable team member to work with (<u>recommendations</u> will speak)

## Zeptolytics (Pvt) Ltd, Colombo, Sri Lanka, [full-time]

Sep 09, 2020 - Apr 30, 2021

## Associate Software Engineer

Sep 09, 2020 - Apr 30, 2021

Responsibilities & Achievements:

- Served my knowledge as a Full Stack Developer (Node.js, Django, Angular, React)
- Promoted within 4 months due to strong performance and organizational impact- ahead of schedule by 8 months
- Put an end to the long-time SEO and mobile performance issue of the company product website by doing various image/ asset optimization and lazy loading which accelerated SEO by +30%, mobile lighthouse performance by +35%, and desktop performance by +30%
- Successfully oversaw and directed the migration of my organization's test environment infrastructure from AWS to DigitalOcean, resulting in a significant cost reduction of over \$400 per month
- Developed and improved company products (**Zepto BI Analytics Tool** and **InsightsPro Tool**)

## Refcoins (Pvt) Ltd, Colombo, Sri Lanka, [full-time]

May 01, 2019 – Sep 01, 2020

## Associate Software Engineer

Jan 01, 2020 – Sep 01, 2020

Responsibilities & Achievements:

- Functioned as a Full Stack Developer (Node.js, React, Flutter)
- Occasionally contributed to product designs and reviews to cover the shortage of UI engineers

 Implemented new features in an existing LMS using Node.js that increased user retention by 10%

## Trainee Software Engineer

May 01, 2019 – Dec 31, 2019

Responsibilities & Achievements:

- Served my knowledge as a Trainee Developer (WordPress, JavaScript, Flutter, PHP)
- Successfully crafted and deployed a custom WordPress theme that advanced website loading speed
- Improved own skills and knowledge through training, workshops, and self-learning

#### FREELANCE PROJECTS

## Ceylinco Virtual Assessor (Back-end) - [ongoing project]

Dec 2022 – Present

An online insurance claims platform advanced for Ceylinco Insurance PLC *Responsibilities & Achievements:* 

- Designed and well-developed a platform for video conferences with clients and claims officers (used Jitsi.org for video conferences)
- Tech Stack & Tools- TypeScript/ NestJS/ Docker/ GitHub Actions

## ATML Fund Management System - Customer Portal (Back-end)

June 2022 – Present

An online customer registration portal with KYC verification for their investors *Responsibilities & Achievements:* 

- Designed and implemented a customer management platform with role-based access and digital client onboarding (KYC) resulting in a 60% improvement in customer satisfaction.
- Tech Stack & Tools: TypeScript / NestJS / AWS / Docker / GitHub Actions / PostgreSQL

#### NON RELATED REFEREE

#### Yasitha Naveen Gunasinghe

Engineering Manager at ReadyTech

naveen.gunasinghe@readytech.io

+61 451 300 533

#### **Indika Pathirage**

Principal Software Engineer at Medtronic

indika.pathirage@medtronic.com

+1 (202) 322 2666